# Alex Thompson

hirealexthompson@gmail.com hirealexthompson.com +81 080-4183-1733 (Japan)

Bachelor of Science Degree in Business Management with a Minor in Leadership. Over eight years of professional experience in application development and geospatial analysis. Adaptable attitude and a demonstrated ability to excel in fast-paced environments. Cleared for Top Secret information and granted access to Sensitive Compartmented Information.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

Bachelor of Science in Business Management with a Minor in Leadership

2007

- Coursework focused on Entrepreneurship, Innovation, and Technology
- Member of the Student Government Association Student Senate, the Student Government Association Budget Board, and the Entrepreneurial Leadership Initiative

#### EXPERIENCE

# **United States Marine Corps**

Geospatial Intelligence Chief, 3d Marine Logistics Group Headquarters G-2, Okinawa, Japan

2015—Present

- Provided geospatial intelligence support directly to the Commanding General of 3d Marine Logistics Group (MLG), in addition to the 12 subordinate units that make up the MLG
- · Led teams conducting annual training exercises and real world operations spanning multiple countries
- Managed the planning and production of hundreds of geospatial products and several internal development projects
- Established a library to organize over four terabytes of in-house and third-party geospatial data
- Nominated for the Military Member of the Quarter award through the National System for Geospatial-Intelligence Awards Program

Geospatial Intelligence Analyst, 3d Intelligence Battalion, Okinawa, Japan

2011-2015

- Collected, analyzed, and processed geospatial data to aid in the production of intelligence products
- Produced intelligence products in support of the III Marine Expeditionary Force and the 36 countries that fall under its area of responsibility in the Asia-Pacific region
- Translated customer requirements into complete intelligence products to meet their needs
- Meritoriously promoted in June of 2013

Raleigh, NC **Progress Energy** 2007-2010

Associate IT Analyst

- Translated business needs into technical requirements for internal customers
- Developed in-house solutions using C# and ASP.NET
- · Assisted with the acquisition of new third-party software solutions
- Managed a software portfolio including more than a dozen applications

### CERTIFICATIONS

- Intermediate Geographic Intelligence Specialist Course, *Honor Graduate* National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency
- Basic Geographic Intelligence Specialist Course, Distinguished Graduate National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Geospatial analysis and data management: ArcMap, ArcGlobe, ArcScene, ArcCatalog
- Front-end design: HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Photoshop
- Web application development: PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, MySQL, C# and ASP.NET